Finding Aid for Camp Al-Gon-Quian (Burt Lake, Mich.) records, 1925-1967
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Staff / Counselors files
  - Alphabetical 1925-1959
    - Der Derian, Arthur (1946)
    - De Tar, Jack (1942)
    - De Vinney, Leland (1935)
    - Doherty, Mr. J. Kenneth (1935)
    - Donahue, Carl (1933-1934)
    - Doty, Mr. Alfred E. (1930)
    - Dutton, Fred (1949)
    - Eckardt, Mr. Bowne (1928-1929)
    - Edwards, Lee H. (1948)
    - English, Gene (1945)
    - English, Robert (1942)
    - Ericsson, Samuel S. (1941)
    - Ernst, Fred (1941)
    - Espeland, Mr. Nels (1930-1932)
    - Evenson, Mr. Clarence O. (1929-1931)
    - Farrior, Dr. Brown (1939)
    - Farrior, Dr. Robert (1934)
    - Feldkamp, Mr. Rolland (1928-1929)
    - Ferguson, Allyn C. (1941)
    - Ferrin, Harvey M. (1934)
    - Flinchpaugh, Mr. James (1930-1933)
    - Follis, William (1938)
    - Freeman, Don (1929-1930)
    - Freyberg, Dick (1926-1931)
    - Fries, Charles (1942)
    - Fry, Bill (1944)
    - Fultz, Keith (1948)
    - Gabel, Mr. Walter (1925) [deceased 1929]
    - Gaddis, Edwin A. (1944)
    - Gaddis, Shirley (1943)
    - Gandall, Mr. John (1930)
    - Garlinghouse, Bruce (1942)
    - Garrett, Bob (1947)
    - Geil, Russell (1933-1934)
    - Genebach, Larry (1942)
    - George, Mr. Henry (1928-1930)
    - George, John (1938) [junior staff]
    - Gibbons, Mr. Sherman (1928-1931)
    - Goodwin, Henry S. (1932)
    - Grace, Mr. James D. (1931)
    - Graham, Garret (1946)
    - Granger, Ned (1940)
    - Gray, Dick (1948)
    - Gray, George F. (1933)
    - Gray, Mr. Harvey (1927)
    - Greenawalt, George (1943)
    - Greene, John (1944)
    - Gresso, Vernon (1944)
    - Grimm, James (1935)
    - Gugle, Frederick B. (1946)
    - Gundersen, Ralph Martin (1949)
    - Hacker, Dave (1943) (Box 26)
    - Hallett, Mrs. Frances (includes Tommy) (1946)
    - Hammond, Geo. M. D. (1941)
    - Hansen, Brynjulf (1946)
    - Harbaugh, Mr. W. D. (1929)
    - Harmon, Louis, 2nd Cook (1925)
    - Harrigan, Mr. Frank (1927-1928)
    - Harvey, Emerson J. (1940)
    - Hawkins, Mr. Harry (1925)
    - Helfrick, Charles K., Jr. (1935)
    - Heneveld, Lloyd A. (1949)
    - Hess, Bill (1944)
    - Hess, John (1943)
    - Higgins, William Robert, Jr. "Bill" (1949)
    - Hill, Dr. Theron (1927)
    - Hills, Charles (1947)
    - Hipwood, Rubee (1949)
    - Hokenson, Mr. Billy (1928)
    - Houghey, David (1936)
    - Hume, H. Ross (1946)
    - Hume, Robert H. (1946)
    - Hutchins, Robert (1926) [died 1927]
    - Ingold, John (1934)
    - Ivanhoff, John (1938)
    - Jacobson, Eric (1938)
    - Jerome, M. D. (1926)
    - Jewell, Ken (1943)
    - Jobe, Mr. William T. (1929)
    - Johnson, Edward (1941)
    - Johnson, Glenn (1941)
    - Johnson, Merlin (1945)
    - Johnston, Mr. Tim (1928)
    - Jones, Bruce DeHaven (1949)
    - Jones, Mr. George B. (1949)
    - Jones, Lloyd (1944)
    - Jones, Mrs. Myra (1949)
    - Jones, Lt. Paul W. (1935)
    - Jordan, John W., Jr. (1949)
    - Kell, Robert (1948)
    - Kellogg, Mr. Stanley (1931-1934)
    - Kent, Mr. Paul (1938)
    - Keppelman, Tom (1935)
    - Kinahan, Fred (1937)
    - King, Lawrence A. (1947)
    - Kishpaugh, Gloria D. (1944-1946)
    - Klein, Maynard (1933-1934)
    - Knechtel, Mr. Otto G. (1925)
    - Koceski, Leo Robert (1949)
    - Krause, Mr. Owen (1928-1930)
    - Kretzschmar, William Addison (1949)
    - Kroske, Carl (1949)
    - Lacker, Bill (1947)
    - La Follette, Ernest (1939)
    - Lane, Robert (1944)
    - Largent, Mr. William (1926)
    - Lashmet, Dr. Floyd (1930-1931)
    - Legault, Mr. Jack B. (1931)
    - Lewis, Clayton (1940)
    - Lickert, Mr. George (1925)
    - Lister, Mr. William (1931-1933)
    - Livingston, Mr. Glenn (1930-1931)
    - Loughlin, W. R. (1931)
    - Lovejoy, Mr. William (1927-1929)
    - Lowry, Mr. George, Jr. (1927-1928)
    - Lowry, Dr. George, Sr. (1928)
    - Lurkins, John (1949)
    - Mann, Oliver D., Jr. (1945)
    - Marceau, J. Edward (1935-1935), 2 folders
    - Marantette, Kenneth (1958)
    - Massey, Kenneth (1941)
    - Matson, Mr. George E. (1927)
    - Matteson, Max Richard (1948)
    - Matthews, David O. (1947)
    - Maxson, Mr. William T. (1927-1930)
    - Maxwell, Dr. J. H. (1930)
    - McCaffree, Chas., Jr. (1933)
    - McCaffree, Charlie "Mac" (1948)
    - McCall, Mr. Robert (1927)
    - McCoy, Mr. Ernie (1928-1932)
    - McCray, Sam (1936)
    - McDowell, James (1945)
    - McFadden, Mr. Bruce (1928)
    - McManus, Ruth (1945)
    - McMillan, Albert (1939)
    - Menzies, Clifford G. (1929-1930)
    - Metzler, Mr. John P. (1929-1930)
    - Miller, Mr. William (1932-1933)
    - Mitchell, Philip H. (1934)
    - Mithofer, Dr. James (1942)
    - Monteith, Mrs. L. (1939)
    - Moore, John C. (1932-1933)
    - Naugle, Gordon Paul (1948)
    - Nederlandon, Bill (1948)
    - Neitzke, Ernest (1934)
    - Noble, Virgil (1943)
    - North, Harold D., Jr. (1930)
    - Northrop, Mr. Phil (1925-1930)
    - Oetjen, Donald V. (1947)
    - Ortmann, Charles H. "Chuck" (1949)
    - Owen, William H. (1947)
    - Parker, Alden (1947)
    - Parker, Louis (1932-1933)
    - Patterson, Mr. Gail "Pat" (1926-1927)
    - Peale, Miss Ruth (1932)
    - Penn, Mrs. Blanche (1944)
    - Petty, Mr. Ross (1928-1931)
    - Phelps, Seth (1936)
    - Philbin, Mr. "Let" (1927-1929)
    - Plenderleith, Ian (1946)
    - Pulling, Mr. Albert Van S. (1930-1933)
    - Pursell, Lester J. (1946)
    - Rawson, Dr. Perry (1936) (Box 27)
    - Reed, Mr. Gerald G. (1926-1931)
    - Rees, Harry Jr. (1937)
    - Rider, Mr. T. Bruce (1926-1931)
    - Riecks, Donald Yale (1945)
    - Rifenburg, Dick (1948)
    - Robare, Mr. Eddie (1925-1929)
    - Roberts, Donald M. (1949)
    - Roberts, Jack (1943)
    - Robertson, Mr. Glen (1928-1930)
    - Robinson, Mr. James (1925-1930)
    - Robinson, James (1946)
    - Romanick, Mr. John (1939)
    - Ross, Fred (1932-1933)
    - Ross, Worth (1948)
    - Russell, Gail "Hap" (1946)
    - Ryan, William M. (1945)
    - Ryder, Joseph Frances (1941)
    - Schaubel, Mr. Ray (1932-1933)
    - Schruben, Bob (1944)
    - Schulz, Dick (1946)
    - Schupp, Jack (1945)
    - Searles, John (1948)
    - Seay, Jim (1948)
    - Selbert, Mrs. Norma (1936)
    - Selleck, Richard (1946)
    - Seymour, Paul (1930)
    - Shellington, Miss Dorothy (1948)
    - Sikorovsky, Eugene (1944)
    - Shields, Mr. Henderson (1926-1931)
    - Simrall, Mr. James "Duckey" (1929-1931)
    - Skeen, Mr. Samuel M. (1931)
    - Slabaugh, Dale (1948)
    - Slaughter, Mr. Edliff "Butch" (1925-1931)
    - Sleight, Mr. James D. (1930-1931)
    - Smith, Mr. Arthur (1930-1933)
    - Smith, Mr. Donald (1925)
    - Smith, Glenn (1948)
    - Smith, W. Dow (1936)
    - Snell, Judson (1938)
    - Soderstrom, Mr. Vic (1928-1930)
    - Spencer, James (1945)
    - Stitt, Mr. Clyde (1936)
    - Stocking, Mr. Bruce "Doc" (1928-1931)
    - Strang, Dr. James (1927)
    - Tefft, Mrs. William (1931)
    - Thiel, Mr. Arthur (1926)
    - Thomas, Dick (1945)
    - Thomas, Kendall P. (1946)
    - Thompson, Raymond (1945)
    - Throop, Harold (1946)
    - Tolfree, John (1948)
    - Traphagen, Mr. Clarence (1925-1927)
    - Unger, Mr. Paxton J. (1927)
    - Van Houten, Charles (1937)
    - Waldron, Mr. Lawrence (1947)
    - Walker, Ted (1942)
    - Wagner, Mr. John (1928)
    - Warner, Mr. Oscar F. (1926)
    - Warthin, Mr. Tom (1927-1928)
    - Wasaquam, Andrew (1941)
    - Watson, Mr. Tom (1926-1932)
    - Weeks, William (1936)
    - Weldon, Richard C. (1949)
    - Wellington, Fred (1941)
    - Wells, William D. (1934)
    - Westerman, Mr. Harold (1938)
    - Westfall, Bob (1940)
    - Wheeler, Lawrence (1935)
    - Whitaker, Wayne L. (1934)
    - Whitely, Mr. Jack (1932)
    - Williamson, Aubra C. (1945)
    - Willis, Kendall (1941)
    - Winchester, Dick (1946-1949)
    - Wingerden, Arthur (1945)
    - Witherspoon, Thomas Worden (1950)
    - Whittemore, Hal (1938)
    - Williams, Richard G. (1950)
    - Wilson, Eugene M. (1945)
    - Wilson, Howard D. (1947)
    - Wood, Mr. Frank A. (1927-1933)
    - Workman, Rollin W. (1950)
    - Wright, Bernard (1942)
    - Wuerfel, Ted (1933)
    - Wyatt, Mr. John B. (1928-1930)
    - Yamagiwa, Mr. Joseph (1931)
    - Yinger, Mr. Dempster (1928-1930)
    - Yinger, Milton (1936)
    - Yinger, Paul (1934)
    - Yacom, Dean (1938)
  - Chronological 1950-1967
    - 1950
      - Ackman, Keith W. (Box 28)
      - Erbe, William E.
      - Harper, James F.
      - Heemstra, Raymond W.
      - Jackson, Virginia Bialy
      - Kretchmar, J. Lauran
      - Price, Evan Charles
      - Slaker, Richard P.
      - Underwood, Dave
    - 1951
      - Bonfiglio, Ralph G.
      - Cronin, Earl
      - Darling, John Allan
      - Gifford, Allan H.
      - Gifford, Bruce G.
      - Guemple, Charles E.
      - Healy, Donald W.
      - Heath, Robert G. (includes Elsye)
      - Marquette, Gene
      - McClelland, Robert L.
      - Server, Harvey W.
      - Staebler, Mike
      - Stuart, Douglas A.
      - Timmerman, Edward G.
      - True, Wesley O.
      - Vreeland, Bruce
    - 1952
      - Atkinson, Don I.
      - Beemer, Richard B.
      - Bennett, Lyle F.
      - Burns, Robert D.
      - Cragg, Graham S.
      - Felzer, Bert L.
      - Goetz, John Thomas
      - Graf, David L.
      - Guettler, Eugene G.
      - Gwinn, Paul Allan
      - Hayes, Edward B.
      - Lewis, Bob
      - Lord, William K.
      - Moore, Harry Clay
      - Moore, Noel Samuel
      - Riedesel, Wilson A.
      - Rogers, Mr. & Mrs. Ralph
      - Schaefer, John David
      - Smith, Dave (includes Steve)
      - Smith, Richard Conrad
      - Stevens, Dale Clinton
      - Wade, Francis M.
      - Walker, Mary Jane
      - Webb, William Duncan (includes Nancy Helen)
      - Weber, Robert Walter
      - Wells, William P.
      - Wilson, Winston Bruce
      - Young, Jon Leon
    - 1953
      - Anderson, Roger A.
      - Barrett, William H.
      - Bateman, William T.
      - Brief, Douglas J.
      - Brown, Richard Seymour
      - Burns, Alden (Monte) B.
      - Chase, Christopher S.
      - Foster, Emerson Clair
      - Gilman, John L.
      - Goodell, David L.
      - Gossett, Tom
      - Hafemeister, Larry
      - Hubly, John A.
      - Nason, Agnes Jane
      - Price, Tom
      - Robles, Rudolph K.
      - Sacquety, Charles W.
      - Smith, Donald F.
      - VanHook, Jim H.
      - Wallgren, Ivan B.
      - Weber, Thomas W.
      - Wilson, Pat
    - 1954
      - Allinder, William F. (Box 29)
      - Bremer, Windham
      - Brown, James R.
      - Bunker, Thomas P., Jr.
      - Coddington, Donn
      - Cowart, Jack L.
      - Cramton, Kenneth G.
      - Elliott, Verda Lillian
      - Enck, Thomas E.
      - Kraus, Willis Keith
      - Lefler, Covert C.
      - Margowski, Johnny
      - Nilsen, Nick
      - O'Neill, Charles B.
      - Pade, Gordon James
      - Struever, Stuart
      - Wanty, Dean J.
      - Wood, David
    - 1955
      - Borusch, Roberts
      - Browne, Brian
      - Conibear, Robert J.
      - Guggisberg, Jamie
      - Jones, Sam
      - Mercke, William F. "Bill"
      - Morris, Mike
      - Richard, Walter
      - Steed, Mrs. Anne
      - Stewart, J. Robert
      - VanderSchalie, Arnold E.
      - Van Fleet, Corey
      - Wallingford, Robert O.
      - Wealch, J. Donald
      - Wear, Robert (includes Louise)
      - Weaver, Richard
      - Wiggins, Jack
      - Wilson, Terry
      - Wilson, Thomas
    - 1956
      - Baldwin, Dick
      - Barton, James
      - Breiholz, Dave
      - Coates, Jim
      - De Waard, Elliott John (Jack)
      - Dunham, Lance
      - Graham, Bill
      - Harrelson, Dave
      - Kress, Tom
      - Larned, Steve (includes Bill)
      - Lasch, Henry Albert
      - Milward, Brint (includes John Burton & Greg)
      - Newburn, Mike
      - Ratterman, Mike
      - Venema, William J.
    - 1957
      - Bogrette, David Wentworth (Box 30)
      - Bush, Paul Earl
      - Conklin, Frederic L., M.D.
      - Davy, Shirley
      - Detwyler, Thomas
      - Enck, Steve
      - Erwin, Jack
      - Farr, Frederick Towne, Jr.
      - Harrelson, Jim
      - Larned, Steve
      - Makowski, Joseph A.
      - Orcutt, William Burton "Bill"
      - Parke, Donald (Mr. & Mrs.)
      - Schreur, David
      - Swadling, Jerry
      - Walsh, Terry Rodney
      - Wuerfel, Frederick P.
      - Zill, Ronald Stephen
    - 1958
      - Arndt, Paul Lambur "Bud"
      - Beach, Gurney D.
      - Burleigh, Charles L. "Chuck"
      - Coulter, Leland Everett Jr. "Pete"
      - Fairbank, Jonathan Thomas "Jon"
      - Fox, James E. "Jim"
      - Jedwill, Fred Warren "Fritz"
      - Meacham, John Palmer
      - McDermott, Dan
      - Miller, Thomas William "Tom"
      - Olson, Raymond S.
      - Powers, Robert Warren "Bob"
      - Richardson, James MacGregor "Mac"
      - Valek, Philip Bryce "Phil"
    - 1959
      - Baldwin, Timothy "Tim"
      - Fenstermacher, Joseph "Joe"
      - Firlik, Robert S. "Bob"
      - Grady, Michael
      - Hillock, Robert Richard
      - Lyke, Murray G.
      - Mayer, George John
      - McCormick, James Hume
      - Miller, George William
      - Murphy, M. Wilson
      - Reed, Michael E. "Mike"
      - Sheasby, John Frederick
      - Shermeta, Dennis
      - Smith, Richard F. "Dick"
      - Weathers, Thomas "Tom"
      - Wilcox, Robert Stimson
    - 1960
      - Ashrafi, Bahman
      - Beuhler, Robert James
      - Cordes, Kurt Lee
      - Dobkin, William Edward
      - Everhardus, John Arthur
      - Fortney, James Milton
      - Geahan, Richard Hale
      - Glass, William Finis, Jr.
      - Goerke, Donald L. (Mr. & Mrs.)
      - Hartsook, David Michael
      - Hodge, Charles Edwin
      - Keating, John Raymond
      - Morison, John A.
      - Nelson, John Allen
      - Peters, David Owen
      - Sluyter, Raymond Edwin
      - Smith, James Douglas
      - Sullivan, Mary Patricia
      - Warner, Jim Bert
      - Weimer, Peter Miller
      - Zbinden, David William
    - 1961
      - Ackerman, Jon Arno
      - Coin, Larry Lavern
      - Colby, William "Bill"
      - Dobson, Russell T.
      - Evans, Kenneth R.
      - Gordon, Robert D.
      - Hodges, Don
      - Hummel, Jerome A.
      - Hush, Lawrence W.
      - Jacobsen, Barry
      - Kriemer, James Dunlap "Jay"
      - Marx, Charles Hardy
      - Maxwell, John W.
      - Wernette, John D. Courcy
    - 1962
      - Albrecht, John (Box 31)
      - Allen, John
      - Berger, Barron D. Jr. "Buzz"
      - Boyer, Thomas Henry
      - Brockman, William George
      - Denise, Jerome Robert "Jerry"
      - Doerr, Richard Samuel
      - Duell, William P. "Bill"
      - Greene, Steven Hardy
      - Haughey, James W.
      - Johnston, Richard Ronald
      - Kinney, Paul E.
      - Klores, Stanley Whitehouse
      - Mewborn, William M. "Doc"
      - Miller, Jr., Robert
      - Munson, Charles T.
      - Nardizzi, Pasquale
      - Nelson, Gregory Karl
      - Readmond, Frances
      - Shambaugh, Gregory Randall "Greg"
      - Viger, David N., Jr.
      - Whitehouse, William
    - 1963
      - Andrews, Paul E.
      - Baker, Robert S. "Bob"
      - Capps, Kenneth Larry "Larry"
      - Clement, Robert Leroy, Jr. "Bob"
      - Creps, Harry James
      - Daley, Leonard Henry
      - Hale, Norman
      - Idema, John Blaine
      - Klein, Gregory Peter
      - Kuehn, William Neal
      - La Bay, Michael J.
      - Liles, John H.
      - McDowell, James William
      - Morse, Peter Harwood
      - Nylund, John A.
    - 1964
      - Bade, James A. "Jim"
      - Beierwaltes, Andrew G. "Andy"
      - Bruggeman, Anthony P. "Tony"
      - Collins, James H. "Jim"
      - Green, Peter Douglas
      - Jankowski, Martin Lee
      - Jones, John R.
      - Krauskopf, John S.
      - McDonald, Dennis
      - Mewborn, Jed Webster "Jed"
      - Murray, William W. "Bill"
      - Retter, Carl R.
      - Rhea, Thomas A. "Tom"
      - Streiff, Karl Daniel "Dan"
      - Van Zon, David D.
      - Walker, Lyle Adams
      - Weber, Lois Jean
      - Whitehouse, Jim Keith
      - Willeke, Robert N. "Bob"
    - 1965
      - Clayton, Thomas S. "Thom"
      - Grady, Steven
      - Graham, John
      - Jones, Jerry C.
      - Kollar, James A.
      - Kollar, John
      - Kriesch, Ronald
      - Ledebuhr, Robert Larry
      - Lonskey, John
      - McDonald, Timothy Joseph
      - Woodruff, Michael Lester
    - 1966
      - Ackerly, Rex C.
      - Bade, Gordon Lawrence "Gordy"
      - Bartlett, Dennis A.
      - Brown, Gary Edward
      - Brunelle, Francis Joseph "Frank"
      - Day, Robert Edwin "Bob"
      - DeFiore, Robert Brian "Brian"
      - Foley, Fred Allen
      - Godwin, Luther P.
      - LaForte, Martin E. "Marty"
      - Leighty, James C.
      - Marshall, Peter Charles
      - Narins, Joseph Paul "Joe"
      - Peters, Richard "Rick"
      - Sandy, Robert "Bob"
      - Schrubkowski, Walentin "Wally"
      - Smith, Rosalie Scott
      - Sperry, Wayne Sheldon "Shelly"
      - Wildeboer, Marcis Kay
      - Wolf, Steven
    - 1967
      - Bauchman, John B.
      - Bryce, Gordon T.
      - Durastanti, Frank
      - Hanke, Kathleen
      - Kell, Gary W.
      - Kollar, James
      - Kollar, John
      - Long, Christopher F.
      - Long, Jon M.
      - Shotwell, James W.
      - Volz, Ken
      - Wilkins, L'Anse
      - Zachrich, Barton M. "Bart"
      - Zink, Jon
    - Staff Miscellaneous
      - Barclay, Charles (1942)
      - Besett, Ferne (1967)
      - Schumm, Albert (1946)
      - Tucker, Randy (1947-1949)
- Administrative and personal
  - Alaska trip 1934, 3 folders (Box 32)
  - Miscellaneous 1950s-1960s forms, etc.
  - 1959
    - Activity Reports
    - Daily health report sheets
    - Form letters
    - Mississaugas camper reports
    - Program
    - Rosters
    - Tribal reports
    - Tutoring
    - Waterfront personnel and rules
    - Miscellaneous
  - 1960
    - Activity Reports
    - Campers
    - Camper reports sheets
      (one cabin retained as sample)
    - Form letters
    - Forms
    - General staff instructions
    - Inventories
    - Program file
    - Reunion file
    - Rosters
    - Staff miscellaneous
    - Tribal reports
  - 1961
    - Campers
    - Camper reports sheets
    - Daily health report sheets
    - Form letters
    - Forms
    - Reunion file
    - Rosters
    - Trip reports
  - 1962-1966
    - American Camping Association 1966
    - Campers 1966
    - Enrollment by area 1963
    - Form letters 1964
    - Program file 1963
    - Religious preference 1962
    - Religious preference 1963
  - Counselor contracts
    - 1958
    - 1960-1961, 2 folders
    - 1963-1967, 4 folders
  - Herbert Twining personal 1961-1966, 3 folders
    (some gaps)